abbottlyon.com 2019-04-22

# Privacy Policy

##### **DISCLAIMER/PRIVACY POLICY**

Abbott Lyon Limited is dedicated to safeguarding the privacy of our website users whilst also providing the highest quality of service possible. All information collected about you will be used lawfully by us, in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) (EU) 2016/679. If there are any requests or queries you have concerning the use of your personal information, please contact help@abbottlyonsupport.com.

This privacy notice tells you about the information we collect from you when you are browsing and purchasing on the Abbott Lyon. In collecting this information, we are acting as a data controller and, by law, we are required to provide you with information about us, about why and how we use your data, and about the rights you have over your data.

**WHO ARE WE?**

We are Abbott Lyon Ltd. You can contact us by email at help@abbottlyonsupport.com.

We are not required to have a data protection officer, so any enquiries about our use of your personal data should be addressed to the contact details above.

**WHAT PERSONAL DATA DO WE COLLECT?**

The information that is likely to be collected from you could be any or all of the following:

  * Name
  * Address
  * Contact telephone numbers
  * Financial information such as credit/debit card numbers
  * IP address, which is automatically collected
  * Web browser type and version, which is automatically collected
  * Operating system, which is automatically collected  
  * A list of URLs relating to your activity on this website, which is automatically collected
  * Cookie information which we provide more information about below.

**WHY DO WE COLLECT THIS INFORMATION?**

We will use your information to verify your payment details for your purchase, process your order and to send you your goods. We will also send you a receipt via email, updates on the progress of your order and we may use your telephone number to contact you regarding your delivery.

We require this information in order to process your payment, deliver your goods and fulfil our contract with you.

This information will also be used for administration purposes.

**WHAT DO WE DO WITH YOUR INFORMATION?**

Your information is stored in our order processing system which is based in Canada and the United States. This system complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework.

Your debit/credit card details are passed to a third-party payment processor which is based in the EEA and is operating under GDPR requirements.

If you are using a third-party payment processor (e.g. PayPal) your payment data will be protected under their privacy policy.

We use various third-party couriers to deliver your goods and we share with them your name, address and telephone number in order to complete the delivery.  

We do not use the information you provide to make any automated decisions that might affect you.

**OUR USE OF THIRD PARTY WEBSITES** ******AND** **SERVICES**

We may, from time to time, employ the services of other parties for dealing with matters relating to payment handling, delivery of purchased items, search engine facilities, advertising, and marketing. The providers of such services do have access to certain personal information provided by any website user. Any of this information is only used by them to perform the services that are requested by us, and nothing else, as this is prohibited.

A list of third parties who your information may be passed onto is available upon request at help@abbottlyonsupport.com.

We do have a marketing department and upon registration or placing an online order we will be notifying you with regards to the order, and the entire transaction process. After the completion of the transaction, we may send across marketing materials if you opted-in to receiving marketing updates or have signed up to receive the Abbott Lyon newsletter. You do however have the option to opt-out of these if you wish.

Furthermore, any of the provided information that is processed by third parties must be processed within the terms of this Privacy Policy and in accordance with the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

Unless we are obliged or permitted by law to do so, and other than the previously mentioned, your information will not be disclosed to any other third parties.

**YOUR RIGHT TO WITHHOLD INFORMATION  **

You can still access certain areas of the website without providing any information at all. However, to use all services and systems available on our website you may be required to submit account information or other data.  

You may restrict your internet browser’s use of cookies.  We provided more information regarding this below.

  **COOKIES**

We use these to provide a better online experience.

Cookies are small text files which are stored on your computer, mobile phone or device. Cookies may be placed on your device when you visit any website or open a marketing email.

Abbott Lyon Ltd. does not use cookies to collect personally identifiable information about you. We use cookies to remember your preferences when you visit our website, to tailor your visit, and monitor traffic to enable us to improve our website, our products, and our services.

We also set third-parties cookies to allow you to easily link to third-party social media platforms or websites. Please visit these third-party websites for more information on these particular cookies.

You can set your browser not to accept cookies and the above websites tell you how to remove cookies from your browser. However, in a few cases, some of our website features may not function if you remove cookies from your browser, but there will not be many.

**ACCESSING YOUR OWN DATA**

You may access your online account at any time to view or amend any of the information that you have provided us with. You may need to modify or update it if your circumstances change, or if any errors have occurred. Additional data as to your marketing preferences may also be stored and you may change this at any time.

You have the right to ask for a copy of your personal information at any time or make the request for anything to be removed.

If you do not wish to receive marketing, promotions or news from us, you can opt-out at any time by emailing help@abbottlyonsupport.com.

Please note that you may change your mind at any time by contacting us by any of the above methods.

**SECURITY**

Data security is of great importance to us and to protect it we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure it all.

There is limited access to your information, the use of passwords is continuous, and we have our computers with the appropriate firewalls.

As previously mentioned, we have put in place browser certification technology and encryption on our website which is why you see the green padlock next to our website address in the bar at the top of your browser. This protects your information and keeps everything private.

When you visit a website that uses HTTPS (connection security), like us, our website's server uses a special certificate to prove our identity to the browser that you are using. To help you stay on safe on the web, many website browsers require websites to use these certificates.

In the unlikely event of a data breach of any sort, this will be rectified in-house with the support of the https://ico.org.uk/. Being as the information we carry on our website and in our marketing details is non-financial, this is not much use to anyone other than ourselves. We are basically a shop and not a service provider. We sell a physical product to you rather than allowing you to use a service that we provide.

No debit/credit card information is held on this website.

**HOW LONG DO WE KEEP YOUR INFORMATION FOR?**

If you create an account and/or make an order with us we will hold your data for seven years to satisfy accounting law.

**YOUR RIGHTS OVER YOUR INFORMATION**

By law, you can ask us what information we hold about you, and you can ask us to correct it if it is inaccurate.

You can also ask us to give you a copy of the information and to stop using your information for a period of time if you believe we are not doing so lawfully.

To submit a request by email, post or telephone, please use the contact information provided above.

**YOUR RIGHT TO C** **OMPLAIN**

If you have a complaint about our use of your information, you can contact the Information Commissioner’s Office via their website at www.ico.org/concerns or write to them at:

**Information Commissioner's Office**

**Wycliffe House**

**Water Lane**

**Wilmslow**

**Cheshire**

**SK9 5AF**

**DISCLOSURES**

Abbott Lyon Limited will not pass your information to any third parties except in the above mentioned circumstances.

If you wish to stop receiving any information about Abbott Lyon Limited and our services please contact help@abbottlyonsupport.com.

**ACCURACY OF INFORMATION  **

Although we aim to have every picture and description accurate, mistakes do occur so please inform us if you see or read something that is not accurate.

If you’ve purchased something based on a picture or description on the website which turns out to be incorrect we’ll happily replace or refund the product.

**PAYMENT**

In order to be able to offer you Klarna’s payment options, we will pass to Klarna certain of your personal information, such as contact and order details, in order for Klarna to assess whether you qualify for their payment options and to tailor the payment options for you.  

General information on Klarna you can find here. Your personal data is handled in accordance with applicable data protection law and in accordance with the information in [Klarna’s privacy policy](http://cdn.klarna.com/1.0/shared/content/legal/terms/Klarna/en_gb/privacy).
